Finding Aid for the Richard Montague papers LSC.0264
UCLA Library Special Collections
Richard Montague papers
1948-1972
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.0264
20.4 linear feet (40 boxes, 1 oversize box, and 1 document box)
Richard Montague was a mathematician, theorist and UCLA Professor of Philosophy, known as the namesake behind Montague Grammar theory of natural language semantics. The collection consists of correspondence, lecture notes, research notes, and personal materials relating to Montague's role as an organist.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page
Box 41 is restricted due to privacy restrictions including PII and FERPA. Please contact Special Collections reference (spec-coll@library.ucla.edu) for more information.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed audiovisual materials. Audiovisual materials are not currently available for access, unless otherwise noted in a Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the series and file levels. All requests to access processed digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift from Edgar Montague, 1971. Addition donated by the UCLA Department of Philosophy in 2013.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9924702633606533
Biography/History
Richard Montague was born in Stockton, California on September 20, 1930. Montague studied philosophy at the University of California, Berkeley, receiving his bachelor's degree in 1950. During his graduate work, Montague studied mathematics and philosophy with Alfred Tarski at Bekeley. His dissertation, Contributions to the Axiomatic Foundations of Set Theory, contained groundbreaking work on axiomatic set theory and helped propel Montague's academic career forward. Montague received his master's degree in mathematics from Berkeley in 1953 and his doctorate in the same subject in 1957.
Montague began teaching at UCLA in 1955 as a professor of Philosophy. While there, he continued research into natural language semantics and formed an approach that would become known as Montague grammar. His thesis was that natural languages and formal languages contain no theoretical differences in terms of comprehension of syntax and semantics.
Montague died on March 7, 1971 in Los Angeles, California after being strangled in his home. His murder currently remains unsolved.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of professional and personal materials relating to mathematician and UCLA Professor of Philosophy, Richard Montague. The papers includes correspondence, lecture notes, research notes, and a manuscript of a monograph written by Solomon Feferman and Richard Montague. Subject files include conference notes, drafts of unpublished papers, and lecture notes from Montague's mentor, Alfred Tarski. Personal materials include programs, announcements, and brochures relating to Montague's role as an organist.
Organization and Arrangement
Collection is arranged in the following series:
Series 1: Feferman - Montague Monograph
Series 2: Lecture Notes
Series 3: Personal
Series 4: Philosophy of Language (Miscellaneous Research Notes)
Series 5: Subject Files
Series 6: Addition
Language and languages -- Philosophy.; Philosophy.
- Series 1: Feferman - Montague Monograph
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are available for access. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  - Correspondence & publishing agreement. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Dittoed material - Chapters 1-3, etc. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - [Loose pages]. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Chapters 1-2, old version. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Chapters 3-4, second copy (with letter about directness theorem). (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Chapter 2, theorem 4, carbon. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Chapter 4. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Chapter 2. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Continuum of relative interpretability types (abstract). (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Chapter 1. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous 2. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Chapter 8. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Chapter 6. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Chapter 7. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Chapter 3. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Chapter 5. (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Independently axiomatizable theories, abstract & early notes. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Goedel-Feferman theorem. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Generalization of Goedel's two theorems (symposium paper, etc.). (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - General formulations of Goedel's second underivability theorem. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Extremes of Goedel's second incompleteness theorem, talk in Chicago., April 1965. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Philosophic Implications of the Gödel Incompleteness Theorem-ASL Meeting Chicago, 1965 April 30; uclayrlsc_0264_009_005_001a; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:09:18) 7 inches (Box 9, Case 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Content Note: corresponding paper insert and CD included in folder.
    - Philosophic Implications of the Gödel Incompleteness Theorem-ASL Meeting Chicago, 1965 April 30; uclayrlsc_0264_009_005_001b; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:20:23) 7 inches (Box 9, Case 1)
  - Chapter 9. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - [Incomparable theories]. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - [Relative interpretability]. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Chapters 1-9 off[icial] copy. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Errors of Way & Mostowski. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Chapter 10 (strongly arithmetical, or set theoretical theories). (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - [Miscellaneous 1]. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - [Loose pages]. (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Feferman. Arithmetization of metamathematics in a general setting. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Feferman pencilled class notes. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Feferman thesis. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Feferman: lecture notes on metamathematics. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Church, manuscript on formal theories. (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Series 2: Lecture Notes
  - Philosphy 12A (Berkeley)., Summer 1969. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    General note
    See also: Rules of thumb, infallible.
  - Philosphy 12A (Berkeley)., Summer 1969. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Predicate calculus: how to eliminate descriptions (and other definite singular terms). (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Philosophy 232B., & Amsterdam., official dittoed notes --- pp.1-52 (elementary syntax)., Fall 1965 Spring 1966 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Philosophy 232 B., & Amsterdam., official dittoed notes --- pp.52-95 (non-elementary syntax)., Fall 1965 Spring 1966 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Philosophy 231, dittoed notes, official., January 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Philosophy 232B., Fall 1965. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Pragmatics & intensional logic, notes & talks. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Pragmatics (paper), supplementary materials. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Pragmatics & language., Spring 1966. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - On the nature of some philosophical entities (abstract). (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Philosophy 240, set theory., lecture notes., Spring 1959 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Philosophy 240, set theory., lecture notes., Spring 1962 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - [Notebook, untitled]. (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
  - [Philosophy 127A / 287]. (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  - Philosophy 221, set theory. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Philosophy 221C., Spring 1967. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Philosophy 127 / 287., Winter/Spring 1970. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Philosophy 192, philosophy of language., Fall 1958. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Philosophy 127 / 287., Spring 1955. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Philosophy 127 / 287., Spring 1963. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Kalish - Montague text corrections. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Philosophy 32. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Philsophy 32., Winter 1970. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Philosophy., Spring 1964. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Philosophy 31., Fall 1970. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Philosophy 31. --- Includes TA evaluations., Fall 1968 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Philosophy 31., Fall 1967. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Philosophy 31., Winter 1967. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Philosophy 31., Fall 1963. (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Philosophy 31., Fall 1956. (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Philosophy 31., Spring 1956. (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Philosophy 31., Spring 1956. (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Philosophy 30, inductive logic., Spring 1956, Fall 1958, Spring 1960. (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Philosophy 126, philosophy of science., Fall 1956. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Philosophy 126, philosophy of science., lecture notes., Spring 1956 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Philosophy 126, philosophy of science., lecture notes., Spring 1959 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Philosophy 126, philosophy of science., student notes., Spring 1960 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Graded papers removed to restricted box 41.
  - Philosophy 222., lecture & student notes., Fall 1963 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Philosophy 222., student notes (end section missing)., Spring 1965 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Philosophy 223., lecture & student notes., Spring 1963 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Philosophy 226., lecture & student notes., Winter, Spring 1967 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Philosophy 221A-C., class notes., 1964/1965 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Philosophy 231., lecture notes., 1964/1965 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Philosophy 186, Epistemology, lecture notes & final exam., Fall 1965 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Mathematics 290G (Berkeley), Foundations of set theory., Spring 1961. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Mathematics 223, Advanced topics in set theory., 1967-1968. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Mathematics 135A (Montague taught at Berkeley)., Fall 1960. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Philosophy 240, recursive functions., lecture notes., Fall 1969 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Philosophy 260., 1967-1968. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Philosophy 262B, recursive functions., Spring 1969. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Philosophy 262A, philosophy of language., Fall 1968. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Philosophy 241., Spring 1957. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Philosophy 241, dittoed material., Spring 1956. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Philosophy 241., Kleeve., Spring 1958 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Philosophy 241., dittoed material., Fall 1961 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Philosophy 241., Fall 1961. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Philosophy 135., lecture & student notes, exam., Spring 1962 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Philosophy 135., lecture notes., Spring 1959 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Philosophy 135., lecture & student notes, exams., Spring 1964 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Philosophy 135., lecture & student notes., Spring 1969 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Philosoph 128, philosophy of mathematics., student notes., Spring 1967 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Philosophy 128, philosophy of mathematics., lecture notes., Spring 1967 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Philosophy 128., lecture & student notes, exams., Fall 1961 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Philosophy 128., lecture & student notes., Fall 1964 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - UC Berkeley, Philosophy 185. --- Student notes while at Berkeley, miscellaneous, including TA notes., Fall 1957, Fall 1959 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - UC Berkeley, Philosophy 185., Spring 1955. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - UC Berkeley, Mathematics 150A, with Loeve. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - RM's student notes from Mathematics 290V (model theory), Tarski-Vaught., 1960-1961. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - RM's student notes from Tarksi's Math 225A., 1948-1949. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - [UCB - RM] Mathematics 202 (), with Bredon., Spring 1961 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Mathematics 202 (Spanier), problems & notes., Fall 1960. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Mathematics 3B., Berkeley, Montague T.A., Spring 1954 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Math D & Math 2, Berkeley., Montague T.A., Fall 1954 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Philosophy 184., Fall 1957. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Philosophy 134., lecture notes & final exam., Fall 1958 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Philosophy 134., Fall 1959. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Philosophy 134., Winter 1969. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Philosophy 134., lecture & student notes., Spring 1970 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - [Unidentified notes]. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Philosophy 6A-6B., 1956-1957. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Philosophy 260., mathematical philosophy., Fall/Winter 1967-1968 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Philosophy 127 & 287., Winter/Spring 1970. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Philosophy 127/287. Dittoed class notes, file copy., Winter/Spring 1970. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Philosophy 262A., dittoed notes., Fall 1963 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Philosophy 260., dittoed notes, file copy., Fall 1967 & Winter 1968 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Philosophy 262A., partial., Fall 1968 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Philosophy 262., philosophy of language --- Includes class roster & enrollment cards., Fall 1968 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Pragmatics: Charles Howard, modal logical. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Philosophy 260, extra copy of dittoed notes on analysis of natural language. (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Series 3: Personal
  - Publicity (personal). (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Recital, concert, play programs (events in which I am not a participant), miscellaneous bulletins. (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - [Programs]. (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Choral music. (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Organists' & choral directors' guilds. (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous church & organ business. (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Letters connnected with process. (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Combinations, references to music. (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Musical announcements, programs. (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - [Investment brochures]. (Box 40, Folder 15)
- Series 4: Philosophy of Language (Miscellaneous Research Notes)
  - Davidson (notes on his papers). (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ordinary language: English as a formal language, talks (Vancouver & abstract, Milan, Los Angeles). (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - On the nature of certain philosophical entities, notes on. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    See also: Philosophy 260, Fall '67 and Winter '68.
  - On the nature of certain philosophical entities: talks, notes & abstract. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous research notes., June 1969-. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Analysis of ordinary language: miscellaneous materials. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Intensional verbs & Berkeley's argument. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Intensional logic & some of its connections with ordinary logic: talks. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Berkeley class., lecture notes., Summer 1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The role of formal logic. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Symbolization. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Universal grammar: talks & correspondence. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Pragmatics: subjunctive conditionals. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Pragmatics 2. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Notes during, most of which led to the paper Universal grammar., Fall 1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Proper treatment of quantification in ordinary English language: talk at Berkeley. --- Correspondence only., February 1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Universal grammar, manuscript. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - English as a formal language I, manuscript. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - English as a formal language, manuscript. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - On the nature of certain philosophical entities, manuscript. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Intensional logic & some of its connection with ordinary language: notes. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous notes:, October 1968-May 1969. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Logical analysis in ordinary language. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - English as a formal language. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - On the nature of certain philosophical entities. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - English as a formal language I, Zerox of typescript. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - The paradox of the stone. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Chomsky, etc.: bibliographic references, articles. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Recursiveness of syntactic categories. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - The proper treatment of quantification in ordinary English: talks, latest version. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Proper treatment of quantification in ordinary English, typescript. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Proper treatment of quantification in ordinary English: talks, all but latest version. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Pragmatics (paper): notes concerning. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Ordinary language: English as a formal language, notes. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Ordinary language, analysis of. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Pragmatics & intensional logic: paper. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Referential opacity, sense data, intensional data. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Pragmatics 1. (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Series 5: Subject Files
  Restrictions on Access
  Portions of this series are restricted.
  - Montague biobibliography. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - [Notebook Miscellaneous]. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Student [job posting]. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous requests - pending. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Reprint (reprint series). (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Tarski - Festschrift. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Grants - NSF [National Science Foundation] submitted, March 1969. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Academic appointments, grants, fellowships, professional matters. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Albuquerque: talk & prospectus. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Appointment to UCLA memorabilia. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Arithmetical classes: extension to the transfinite. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Arithmetical classes (semi-axiomatizes). (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Arithmetical extensions. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Automata. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Automata, selected reprints on. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Calculus of ought, Montague. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Calculus of prenex forms. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Carnap: foundations of physics. (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Carnap: applications of logic (from logical theory course). (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Carnap's probability book, notes. (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Carnap probability notes. (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Carnap: probability seminar. (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Carnap, Schlipp volume. (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Chang's lectures. (model theory)., Fall 1964 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Chang's seminar on undecided theories, McLaughlin's report. (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Chang's seminar on semantics. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Chang's seminar., model theory with values in a uniform space., Spring 1962 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Cocciarella, dissertation. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Consistency of set theory, relative consistency theories. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Contributions to the axiomatic foundations of set theory, copy 3. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Contributions to the axiomatic foundations of set theory, old copy 2. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Contributions to the axiomatic foundations of set theory, copy 4. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Contributions to the axiomatic foundations of set theory, notes & sketches. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Convergence in topology. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - DeBouvere: bilateral interpretability & synonymity. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Definable models of set theory. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Degrees of unsolvability. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Deterministic theories, manuscript. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Deterministic theories, with revisions sent to Washburne & note from Markovic. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Deterministic theories, notes & revisions. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Differential equations (corrected with determinism). (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Doubly recursive functions. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Editorial responsibilities, Journal of Philosophical Logic. (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Editorial responsibilities, The Philosophical Forum. (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Effective operations, etc. (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Gaifman, model theory, class at UCLA., Spring 1968. (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Gunderson, cybernetics. (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Functional calculus which holds in the null domain. (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Frege. (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Friedman (prenex nf proof). (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Hemphill & Oppenheim on explanation (Eberle, Kaplan & Montague). (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Herbrand theorem - attempts. (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Higher-order logic: foundations of. (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Higher-order logic: reductions of. (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Higher-order logic: reductions of, manuscript. (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Higher-order logic: Kurtzman. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Higher-order logic: recent problems. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Higher-order logic: Craig's lemma & 2nd order model theory (?). (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Higher-order logic: miscellaneous. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Higher-order logic: set theory & higher-order logic. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Higher-order logic (see also black notebook). (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Higher order structures. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Hyper-arithmetic hierarchy. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Incomparable theories (abstract). (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Interpretability in terms of models. (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Interpretability vs. relative interpretability. (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Intensional logic: Dana, David, manuscript. (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Intuitionism, recursiveness. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Iota theories. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Kalicki's seminar. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Keisler's talk, with comments. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Keisler, et al. Model theory, notes on lectures at UCLA., 1967-1968. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Keisler, dittoed notes from UCLA model theory class., Fall 1967. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Keisler, notes on model theory from Wisconsin. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Kreisel & Wang paper, my notes on. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Kreisel, two expository notes on foundations (for set theory symposium book)., Summer 1967. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Kreisel, two notes ... (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Kripke. (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Letters, miscellaneous from logicians. (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Letters, miscellaneous, university business. (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Letters., 1966. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Letters., Spring 1966. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - [Letters., 1965]. (Box 21, Folder 3-4)
  - [Letters., 1964]. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - [Letters., 1963]. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Letters sent, (copies), [, 1961-1962]. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - [Letters., 1962]. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - [Letters., 1961]. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Letters, telegrams received., June-August 1958. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Letters received., January-February 1958. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Letters received., September-December 1957. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Letters received., late 1957, early 1958. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Letters., 1955-1956. (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Letters of recommendation. (Box 22, Folder 9-10)
  - Letters., professional correspondence., 1960-1961 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Letters (including paradox regained correspondence)., 1959, 1960. (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Lewis, David. (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Letter to Tarski., 19 March 1957. (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Levy's first axiom: Tarski's axiom of inaccessible sets. (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - London., June 1966. (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Long. (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Logic notes, miscellaneous. (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Logic of science. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Logic: techniques, corrections, 4th set ()., November 1965 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Logic: techniques for formal reasoning, some correspondence. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Logic: techniques ..., miscellaneous improvements, remarks & corrections. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Logical necessity, physcial necessity, ethics and quantifiers. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Logical necessity ... revised version, manuscript & carbons & galleys. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Mahlo numbers, inaccessibles. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Mailings of reprints, etc., record of mailings ()., before 1970 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Mailings of reprints & copies of papers (record of)., 1970-. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Mathematical Reviews. (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Mattison. (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - McLaughlin. (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - McLaughlin, recursive foundation seminar., Spring 1962. (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - McNaughton. (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Modal logic. (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Models for set theory (notes on Tarski's manuscript). (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Model theory: lectures at LSE () & UBC () & LSE ()., June 1966 July-August 1968 1962 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Model theory: miscellaneous. (Box 23, Folder 18)